3 Months Later
Near Yalakova
Visit turkision.com for more!
Praise be to the army.
There will be Turkmen tents
throughout seaside of Yalakova.
Today is the day.
Bursa will be surely
conquered when the time comes.
We are sure of that. However..
..if we do not prevent the support
that will come from Constantinople..
We will not be victorious..
..in the siege.
We need to lift the siege..
..for every support that comes, my Bey.
-We need to secure the roads.
-Before the siege..
..Yoruks, Armutlu, Cinarcik..
..and Yalakova will be where they will camp.
They will stay there .
Orhan, did Gunduz Bey's alps settle in Yalakova?
They are on their duty to
ensure Yoruks' safety, my Bey.
-Good.
-Our other alps are at Armutlu.
They are taking precautions, my Bey.
These places that we are camping..
..will start closing off in
the shape of a crescent.
That way..
..siege of Bursa will begin.
If Allah permits.
We are taking every precaution on land.
They still have the seas.
We will continue the siege.
And here, Karesi Bey..
..you will have a lot to do.
I am honored by your invitation, Osman Bey.
However, we've lost a huge part of the fleet..
..from the attacks of Katalan.
Our ships are not enough..
-..to stop Byzantine ships.
-If this was easy..
..everyone would've conquered Bursa.
Alaeddin Bey arrived at the lands of Karesi..
..to complete the shortcomings
of the fleet, my Bey.
He took blacksmiths and wood craftsmen with him.
Good. Now..
..Karesi Bey, we will stop all the help..
..coming from the sea.
And all of the treasure here..
..will be Karesiogullari's treasures.
May you prosper.
May you prosper, Osman Bey.
Either on land or sea..
..Turks always fight.
Yes.
We will either be martyrs for this cause..
..or Bursa will be ours.
There is no other way.
Where is the gold?
There is no gold. We are paying our taxes.
No., gold..
Don't do this!
We are already paying our taxes!
We do not have the power
to give war taxes anymore!
Have mercy!
This injustice acts of yours
will be your end someday.
People of Bursa are not happy with war taxes.
If we lose people's support-
To hell with the people!
I came here with the permit from the Emperor.
The sheep of Jesus will either give their wool..
..or their meat!
Osman is getting ready to cut our
connections with Constantinople..
..before attacking Bursa!
If they want to leave
safely, they will pay the price.
Soldier.
All of you want to chew on
this juicy Bursa peach, right?
However, know that this amazing taste..
..comes from the core of the peach!
This core is the army of Byzantine itself!
You are here because the army is here!
If the army is gone, then
you will all starve to death!
This is a robbery! Will you take our lives too?
We don't have the means to hold on anymore.
Please, have mercy. Our businesses..
..are on the verge of ending.
You will end businesses! Don't do this!
No mercy!
I will pull each of your teeth out..
..that wants to bite this juicy fruit!
Open shields!
Don't be afraid. Run to your home.
Come on, run to your mother.
Come on.
We need to tell Osman Bey what happened. Let's go.
-A letter for Osman Bey.
-Boran.
The letter is from Constantin Paleologus.
The dog who ordered to kill Gunduz Bey.
-What does he want, my Beys?
-He says he speaks with the emperor's order.
He wants to meet and talk.
-That's what we want.
-They know every step of ours, my Bey.
Yes, they do.
But they also know what we'll do to them.
He's now inviting the one
who he desired to kill once.
He wants to meet...
...the one who he wanted to kill.
Let's see him.
-Will we meet him, my Bey?
-Yes.
We will meet Constantin.
To stop us,
...he will certainly try several tricks.
In fact, he will even attempt to kill us.
Yet I can't wait for Bursa's conquest...
...to avenge Gunduz Bey.
I will decide even the commander who is going
to be my enemy during the conquest of Bursa.
This man is too vile to be my enemy.
-Orhan.
-My Bey.
You and I will go to Bursa.
There's been no news from Holofira for long.
We need to find out how she's been doing.
As you order, my Bey.
Giddap! Giddap!
Mercy is a huge lie, Aleksios.
The only solution would be a sharp sword.
If Osman doesn't come around
...he will face my sword's sharp side.
Even if he accepts your invitation,
...he won't have an agreement
with you, Commander Constantin.
I invited Osman to
get to know him...
...and kill him at the first
chance, not to have an agreement.
If Osman dies in Bursa,
...our honor will be ruined.
People will see us as cowards.
Honor... It's a stupid word.
When Osman destroys the city walls,
...there will be no honor and people left.
Besides, it's not me who will kill Osman.
He won't be killed in the palace.
It will look like people lynched him.
Now it's time to talk to my beloved cousin
Holofira who I haven't seen for long years.
When I last saw her she was a little kid.
She's not a kid anymore.
She is a smart woman with a sharp mind.
We'll see whether she'll serve
her own kin with her mind...
...or serve goat shepherds.
Let's go.
Well... Thank You, my Allah.
-Scholar.
-My dear.
Shall we race to the tribe?
-What? Do you miss your tribe?
-Yes, a lot.
You'll eat my dust then. For your information.
You can't beat me this time, Scholar.
You say so?
-Yes.
-Fine.
Let's see, Trickster Hatun.
We'll see, Scholar.
-To the water source in the valley then.
-Alright.
-Fine. Here we go.
-Here we go.
-Hasan.
-My Shahzade.
Tell the other tribes to meet the needs
of the iron mongers and carpenters...
...who we brought from Karesi lands.
As you order, my Shahzade.
Fine. Here we go. Be careful.
Let's go, Trickster Hatun.
You've got slow since we got married, Scholar.
No. This isn't the case. I just let my wife win.
Oh come on. Can't you just admit that you lost?
Well, my dear... You win.
Tell me. What do you want from your husband?
I want nothing.
This was our last horse race.
Oh really? Why is that?
I'll tell you. But promise not to yell.
Just say it.
Great news, Alaaddin Bey.
What news, Gonca?
-Alaaddin.
-Yes, my dear?
-I can't ride a horse anymore.
-What is the matter?
Alaaddin...
I'm pregnant. We're going to have a baby.
Pregnant?
-Pregnant...
-I'm pregnant.
We're going to have a baby.
What are you saying, my Gonca?
I am... -You are pregnant.
-I am pregnant.
Allah!
My Allah, thanks to You!
Stop... stop...
You are pregnant... I am going to be a father.
I am going to be a father... What should
I do now, my Gonca? What should I do?
I'll go and wash
my face, Gonca.
Where are you going, Alaeddin?
I'll go and wash my face, Gonca..
-Alaeddin...
We are going to have a child!
Stop, what are you doing?
Alaeddin...
-We are going to have a baby.
Allah..
GERMIYANOGLU BORDER - FRONTIER MARKET
Welcome to Kayi's property, Yakup Bey.
It is Osman Bey's order. From now on...
...when you come to the marketplace...
...your Alps will leave their swords, Yakup Bey.
Why do you take our Alps' sword, huh?
How dare you?
-Osman Bey's property...
...Osman's laws, Mehmet Bey!
We will come to collect taxes tomorrow
we came here to let you know that.
I did not come here to fight with you.
Move!
Swords, Yakup Bey.
As if giving taxes to Osman is not enough...
...now they are treating us like this.
They say we can't trade with anyone else..
He said he would stop us from trading with...
..Bursa and Iznik.
Arrogant man...
Now you cannot trade with
Byzantium as well, father.
And now Yoruks are also
pledging allegiance to him.
All tribes see Osman Bey as
a spiritual leader, my Sultan.
He has no spirituality. -Right.
He is enlarging his treasury with those raids.
He is feeding people...
...and he also takes those things from us.
-We did not...
...come here for gold, Mehmet.
Trade is just an excuse.
We are not here to be humiliated.
I know what I will do to him.
This is Yakup Bey's word.
Bala.. -Welcome, my Bey.
-Thank you.
So? Where are Alaeddin and
Gonca? Haven't they returned yet?
They are coming, my Bey!
There is something strange.
What happened, Alaeddin? Gonca?
I have good news, my Bey.
Now we will put another plate on our table.
What?
With Allah's consent, we
will have a child, my Bey.
Praise be, this is such good news!
Praise be.
My daughter...
May it be blessed..
-Thank you mother.
-May it be blessed. May it be blessed.
-Thank you my Bey.
Mother... -My son..
My daughter... May it be blessed.
-Thank you, my Bey...
Praise be, praise be.
I hope you will come
together with your child safely.
I hope so, mother.
-Brother..
-My lion brother..
May Allah let you raise your child in pace.
Boran Bey...
Praise be.
So, Boran.. -My Bey!
Sacrifice 40 animals and
distribute them to the people!
Kayi is expecting a grandchild!
Yes my Bey!
May it be blessed. -Thank you.
Now I am going to be an aunt, huh?
What am I going to be then?
I am going to be an uncle!
Right, right... Little uncle...
Come on Ulgen... We have to set a well-prepared...
...table after this news, huh?
We will set the best of it.
Let's go inside.
Now, they say girls look like their aunt..
...and boys look like their uncle.
I hope she will look like me, huh?
Why would he look like that big Mehmet?
Huh? That's not true.
If it's a girl, she will look like you,
if it's a boy, he will look like me.
Right... One Mehmet is enough for me.
He will look like his uncle for sure.
But... One Fatma is also enough, brother.
Brother... I am offended.
Wait, aunt, wait...
Why are you carrying that?
What harm could this little
thing possibly do, Fatma?
You are pregnant! Why are you being stubborn?
Oh praise be... Praise be.
What a beautiful table you have set...
Thanks to Allah. We are growing day by day.
Right... Thanks to Allah
Who let us see these days.
Come on now, sit down. -Come on.
My Bey, Biiznillah we sacrificed our
animals and distributed them to our people.
Good, good.
Keep distributing it to Sogut and Yenisehir.
Yes my Bey.
-Orhan.
-My Bey..
You will come to Bursa with me.
Alaeddin. -My Bey...
You will stay here. You
will provide the security here.
But... you will protect my daughter-in-law.
Yes, my Bey. -No...
...my daughter is entrusted to me, right?
Thank you.
Gonca..
Today, your father Yakup Bey and Mehmet...
...came to the marketplace.
You gave us the good news and made us happy.
If you wish, you can also give
the good news to your father.
I mean... What happened between
your father and us is different.
So that he is going to have a grandchild...
...your father has to know, right?
Right, Bala? -Yes.
Besides, this might help you make peace, huh?
I don't know...
Do you think his heart softened?
As you wish. It's your choice.
Come on now. In the name of Allah,
the merciful, the compassionate
Thank you my Bey.
Here, my daughter.
How are you, cousin Holofira?
It's been years, right?
So you remembered you had a cousin, Constantine.
I thought you buried me alive here.
While you were in the dungeon..
...I conducted a detailed investigation about you.
I had to find out...
...what happened between you...
...and the Kayis and Orhan especially.
I learned. Orhan...
...stole your heart first...
...then married a Bey's daughter.
He let you down just to get stronger.
If you are happy now, allow
me to go to the monastery.
After completing your service to Byzantium,
you can start living in seclusion, Holofira.
What do you want from me?
Osman Bey and his son Orhan..
...will come to Bursa as my guests.
But they will never return to their tribes.
Why should I care? They can all go to hell.
Amazing! Then..
...you'll help me kill them when
they return from Bursa to their tribes.
Do you think killing your
guests here does not suit you?
It is politically wrong, of course.
But morally right, isn't it?
Because they are Turks.
I will happily assist you.
This duty is holier than going to the monastery.
Then go to the room I prepared for you.
Have master tailors sew beautiful clothes for you.
Choose the best one.
Get your hair done.
Look beautiful for Orhan, who still loves you.
Hide your anger.
Do your duty.
-What am I going to do?
I'll tell you when the time comes.
Now... now I will ask something from you.
While my father was dying..
..were you with him?
Yes, why did you ask?
I was wondering about his last words.
There was never anyone that I could've asked.
No matter how brave one is..
..they love living, Holofira.
He begged to live as well.
However, he betrayed the Emperor.
Just like every traitor, your
father was hanged to death.
We tried really hard to not let him die.
We wanted to have him exiled.
However, Emperor did not accept.
However, you, Holofira.
You will show your loyalty to The Emperor.
You will lift that dark stain..
..on your family.
You despicable liar.
Elcim, are you alright?
I was distracted, sorry.
I did not see you coming.
When Gonca Hatun gave the good news..
..I remembered.
My father wanted to see his
grandchildren too, however..
However what, Hatun?
With Allah's permission,
we will have children too.
Don't you think I know you've
been sewing these in secrecy?
My brother Alaeddin.
It is like he just declared
his love to Gonca yesterday.
And now he will be a father.
In the same way..
..we will have children at times
we least expect it, if Allah permits.
Our children will grow up in this tribe together.
They loved each other.
Their child is a fruit of their love.
Our child..
..will be the knot that ties two tribes together.
A knot of a Grand State.
Of course, a knot of the Grand State.
The knot of Grand State that
will make many tyrants kneel.
If Allah permits, our children will
see to many duties just as we do.
Only if Allah permits.
Holofira is at Bursa as well.
So what, Hatun?
We are heading to Bursa
for duty, don't you know that?
Look at me.
I've buried my love deep beneath the dirt.
You know that best. We are
not heading to Bursa for Holofira..
..but to kill Konstantin, who
gave the order to kill your father.
Elcim, we are going to Bursa..
..for you. To keep the promise I gave you..
..and ease the pain in your heart.
Do not.
Do not ever..
..question my loyalty. Do not ever.
Father! Father!
Holofira! Holofira!
Holofira!
Holofira, don't cry for
your father! He is a traitor!
You are a daughter of a noble
mother, now go back to her!
You will live as a noble princess in our kingdom!
Holofira. I am not a traitor.
Do not forget that I've died
as an honorable commander.
-Do not ever forget that.
-Father!
Father! Father!
-Stop.
Murderers.
Commander Konstantin.
I am at your service.
I am giving you an important duty.
Orhan and Holofira.
You know them well, right?
You are a witness to their love.
Now..
..you will ensure that
Holofira is telling the truth.
My gazelle-eyed.
These whites on your hair..
And?
-What, Osman Bey? Are you saying I am old?
-No.
However, our children grew up, being a father now.
-And you..
..are being a grandfather, Osman Bey.
I am.
Thank Allah, for showing us these days.
Thank Allah. I am already excited.
Even if we get old, it is fine.
These whites on your hair..
..I love them the most.
Do you know why?
-Why?
-We got in love..
..became home, became family..
..these trees we have planted,
are now giving their fruits.
Those whites on your hair..
..is a witness to that.
And I remember the times we
spent together, after seeing them.
My dear, what are you doing?
-Just making the bed.
-Hey, stop.
From now on, it's my duty to tidy up.
-It's just a light bedspread, Alaaddin.
-No, that's not the case.
Now I'm counting the forbidden
things. Keep them in your mind.
-Forbidden?
-Yes.
Well... From now on, no training.
-No riding.
-And?
No carrying loads.
We live in a tribe, Alaaddin.
What? Will I just stand
idle while there is work to do?
Yes, you will.
You will smile at me just like this.
And I will do the rest.
Let's see what your mother will say.
My mother won't...
...let her daughter-in-law
and the baby get exhausted.
-I know. I know.
-Yes.
Did you consider what my
father said last night, my dear?
I'm going to go to the
frontier market to collect taxes.
Are you coming with me?
It's been a long time.
Do you think my father's heart has softened?
Even if it hasn't,
...it will when he hears about the baby.
I hope so.
But this is my last visit.
I will just do my duty as the daughter.
Alright. So be it. Come to me.
Paleologus is holding the
leash of the jackal called Ulcay.
This invitation must be a trick.
But what trick?
-I don't feel at ease, my Bey.
-Bala.
...we'll ruin the tricks of the
one who is holding the leash...
...just like we sent the
owner of the leash to hell
-Do I have permission, my Bey?
-Come in.
We got a message from Turgay Alp, my Bey.
Constantin...
...slaughtered the people of
Bursa who objected to the war taxes.
Turgay says the screams of
the innocent rise up to the sky.
He has no mercy even for his own people, huh?
Osman, the one who did this
to his kin and coreligionists...
..must be a devil.
May Allah let us face the honorable
enemies... Not like vile ones...
I know, Bala. He can perform any kind of cruelty.
But we have taken measures.
Alps are disguised in Bursa.
They're standing ready.
We'll avenge Gunduz Bey and all the others.
Yet..
Constantin...
The price he's going to pay...
...will be pretty heavy.
I'll give this letter to Orhan
through a servant girl.
Orhan will come here.
You two won’t be alone in the room.
It's very kind of you to care
about me, Constantin. Thank you.
What do you want me to do?
To charm him with your beauty.
To make him regret that he
married that Bey's daughter.
That won't be hard.
He still loves me.
-What else?
-Find out their return route.
I see the hatred in your heart.
Your beautiful eyes miss nothing, my dear cousin.
Now get prepared beautifully.
Daughters shouldn't live their fathers' fates.
Don't you betray me. Don't break my trust.
Otherwise, both of you...
..will pass away in this room.
GERMIYANOGLU BORDER - FRONTIER MARKET
-Welcome, my Shahzade.
-Welcome, Gonca Hatun.
-Thank you, thank you.
-Welcome.
Oh, Kayis!
Welcome to our market.
-Gonca Hatun.
-Don't raise troubles, Mehmed Bey.
-Why are you here? To collect taxes?
-I heard...
...you prepared the taxes. Thanks.
But this isn't the only reason why we are here.
Why are you here, Alaaddin?
Is this your welcoming me after long time?
We're here to see Yakup Bey. Get our of our way.
My father has nothing to tell you.
He doesn't want to see you.
Move aside, Mehmed. If I want to see him, I see.
Watch your words, Alaaddin.
-Don't push me.
-My wife has things to say, Mehmed.
You seem to have forgotten. Let me remind you.
This frontier market is
mine. For your information.
My Shahzade!
My Bey wants to see them.
Help. Help.
Help.
May God bless you.
My children... My children...
Keep your eyes wide open.
If someone attempts to harm Osman Bey,
...we will intervene immediately.
Holy father, take me to heaven too.
Please. I'm begging you.
May Jesus Christ bless you,
...my poor child.
To go to heaven, first...
..you should die.
Estaghfir... Well..
First look for God in the whole world...
-Then you'll find heaven.
-How come?
How?
First start walking from here.
I can't know everything.
May God bless you.
Nikola?
Welcome to Bursa, the most
magnificent city of these lands, Osman Bey.
Good. Rich.
But not as mighty as it should be.
Leave your horses here.
You can't continue on horses.
This is not a Turkish tribe
where you can ride your horses.
Alright. For now, it's not.
Look at me, commander.
Treat our horses kindly.
Make them feel at home.
Well..
If... If they are harmed,
..I will make you pay for this.
Don't be worrying, Osman Bey.
We will host your horses well!
I know their language. If
you do something bad to them,
I will know.
Father, who is that stranger
beside Commander Aleksios?
Osman Bey, Bey of Kayi.
Osman Bey, huh?
Have you come to see the market's condition?
Or to collect taxes Alaaddin Bey?
If you're asking about the market,
we are here for a duty, Yakup Bey.
If you are asking why we wanted to see you,
...we're here because we
respect you as my wife's father.
Her father?
Her father...
Did you think...
...I would forget what you made
me suffer when some time passed?
No. I haven't forgotten.
In Kutahya,
...people still tell each other my
daughter ran away with my enemy.
Don't tire me with your
words. Have a safe journey.
I want to ask, father. I want to know.
Don't you forgive me because people
gossip and your honor is damaged?
Or don't you really want to forgive me?
It doesn't matter anymore.
Mehmed, deliver the taxes...
...and see Kayi people off.
#unrecognized text#
You're going to have a grandchild, father.
Does it matter to you?
No.
I don't have a daughter.
So I can't have a grandchild.
Alright then.
This was my last visit, father.
I did my duty as the daughter.
You rejected us twice before, Yakup Bey.
We thought Muslims should try three times...
...and came here again.
But it's over now, Yakup Bey.
Stay safe.
Let's go, my dear.
My Shahzade, the taxes are loaded.
Fine. Let's go.
Come on!
Commander Konstantin will invite you to dinner.
You can rest at your rooms until then.
The letter came from Holofira,
my Bey. She wants to see me.
Holofira was silent for so long.
Why is she writing a letter now?
Konstantin.
He must know about this as well.
My Shahzade, is this her writing?
It is hers. However, there is one difference.
Holofira wrote the letter
with his father's surname.
Meaning, my Shahzade?
As long as I knew Holofira, she always
wrote them with her aunt's surname.
However, this time she wrote
it with his father's surname.
They are making Holofira write letters by force.
They are trying to pull her
into their tricks, however..
-..she is giving us a sign.
-What will I do, my Bey?
We will give them what they want.
You will see Holofira.
However, you will be cautious.
If Konstantin is behind this..
..this can lead to them killing us even.
They will watch and listen to you when you meet.
-Do not show your intentions.
-As you command, my Bey.
My Bey. What will they get from this in the end?
We will find out about that from Holofira.
However, most probably, their intentions..
..is to learn our route.
They want to handle this without
soaking their hands in blood.
Just as how they did to Gunduz Bey.
Come on then. Let us see the face of the devil.
GERMIYANOGLU BORDER - FRONTIER MARKET
I've brought you gifts..
..from the lands of Kar3si, Yakup Bey.
You shouldn't have, Karesi Bey.
-Kanyumaz.
-My Bey.
Give these to those in need..
-..around the tribe.
-As you command, my Bey.
I thought you were at Kutahya.
I was.
However, after hearing
what is happening at frontiers..
..I couldn't stay at Kutahya.
You've made a deal with Osman.
-Is that true, Karesi Bey?
-You've heard right.
-How can you do this?
-Why is that a bad thing, Yakup Bey?
Who should I support..
..other than Osman Bey for war?
There is a time for everything, Karesi Bey.
The siege of Bursa and
Iznik is nothing but a dream.
The ambitions of Osman..
..will cause trouble..
..to all people.
Can't you see that?
If you know something, say it.
Osman is preparing for Bursa and Iznik now.
What about tomorrow? Constantinople.
Maybe he will send only the soldiers.
All of the people will break..
..with a single mistake from Osman, Karesi Bey.
Turn back while you still have the chance.
Draw back the support you are giving to Osman.
If he stays alone..
-..he will also fall back.
-How will that happen, Yakup Bey?
How can we leave Osman Bey..
-..alone with those jackals?
-There is no need to fail..
..alongside Osman, Karesi Bey.
It is better for Osman to break..
..instead of the people.
Do not worry about treasures as well.
I will personally give you..
..the double what Osman promised you..
..for war.
Welcome, Osman Bey.
Don't you have the courage to talk to me alone?
Look at these guards behind you.
I came to Bursa with four alps.
Osman Bey is disturbed.
All guards leave the room!
I didn't know you
had to be on top..
..to converse with me in the room.
You outnumber me now.
Here, Osman Bey.
You wanted to meet us.
Now you learned who we are.
The things I've heard..
..did not make me happy, Osman Bey.
You are placing nomads..
..on our trade routes on our fertile lands.
One needs to be blind to not
see what you have been doing.
My intention is true.
Before my move..
..everyone knew that.
As long as I breathe..
..there is no way for you
to siege Bursa, Osman Bey.
I think so as well.
Look at the World, Osman Bey.
Every lion, every wolf who tried to siege Bursa..
..has broken teeth now.
Bursa is not a city you can reach.
This city is not like..
..those castles you took.
Those who rule it, are not
like those Lords you defeated.
You are in over your head.
You will cut off all ties..
..between Constantinople and Bursa.
Then what? This city can feed itself for years.
Don't tell me about Bursa. I know very well..
..what kind of a city Bursa is.
The things you just said..
..can never deter me. On the contrary..
..it feeds my ambition.
That is why I want this city.
That will never happen, Osman Bey.
Either with the easy way, or the hard way.
Sooner or later, Bursa..
..will be the land of Turks.
You won't last long enough for that, Osman Bey.
Only Allah knows that. However..
..I will do whatever I
can, so that you won't last.
Now, tell me.
What do you want to speak with me?
Holofira.
You called me?
I did, and you came, as if
you've been waiting for this day.
Are you alright? Why did you call me?
The same reason why you came despite Elcim.
You could've not come as well.
You are right. I shouldn't have come.
Go! Like you always do! Run away!
Holofira.
Are you alright? Did something happen?
You still love me.
Don't, Holofira.
Do not throw the ashes of this love.
Ashes? Has the fire of this love ever gone out?
After everything that happened,
why does that matter, huh?
Have you been able to forget me?
Was this really your love?
Holofira..
I accepted this marriage for my family...
...for my tribe. And you know that.
Yes. I do.
You chose your family, Orhan.
You left me all alone.
But you didn't only betray
me, you also betrayed yourself!
You gave up on your love and married Elcim!
I had no other choice!
But you... you had one, Holofira. What did you do?
You... chose to leave!
Now... What changed, Holofira?
I've been in pain since I came here.
No matter how angry I am..
...I've realized that my love for you...
..will never end.
Holofira... -Why?
How could you betray us while
we loved each other like this?
I will offer you the opportunity
to continue your existence.
Otherwise, you and your people
will march towards your end.
Tell me.
-You will open all the roads you blocked.
We will make you a partner in our trade.
All goods and roads from
Constantinople to Bursa...
...will be under our dominion.
After Bursa, we will leave...
...all the trade of the East to you.
Has no one ever told you that..
...I will not sell gaza for gold?
You don't want gaza..
...you just want to be the best.
I am giving you that.
Be sure you make the right choice.
You have suppressed all the Beys.
You crushed them and have risen.
Even in Constantinople...
...your name is mentioned
as the protector of the Turks.
You cannot protect it this way, Osman Bey.
I am not seeking any way...
...to protect my sultanate.
My path is known. It is the
path of gaza ordered by my Allah.
That path can bring your end, Osman Bey.
I thought we could come to an agreement.
Actually...
..there is one more way.
I would like to hear that. -I will break...
...all your relations with Byzantium.
Your trade will be weak.
It will come to an end after a while.
...if you do not wish to fight against me...
...then you will bring..
...five hundred thousand gold
coins to my tent every year.
If we opened your treasury today, Osman Bey...
...would you have this much gold?
You are the one who wants to make peace with me.
You will make this decision.
Lord is not in Bursa right now.
When he comes, I will talk to him about this.
And I will inform the Emperor
about this with a letter.
You would have wanted it so much, wouldn't you?
What? -Me to...
..pass away to the afterlife like Gunduz
Bey. You would want that so much.
You have my brother's blood on your hands.
You are trying to agree
with me by offering me gold.
From now on, I will never accept any peace...
..that you are a part of.
-You started the war...
...you cannot hold me responsible
for the price you paid, Osman Bey.
If you do not stop this war...
...Gunduz Bey...
...will not be the last one to die.
We are not afraid of death.
If we were..
...we wouldn't have come to Bursa.
This will be a long war.
But only I will decide...
..who will die and who will survive.
Constantine...
Speak! Why don't you speak, Orhan?!
Tell me something! How could you betray us?
Holofira...
What are you doing, huh?
Are you going to kill me with your love...
...or are you going to have Constantine kill me?
I don't need anyone to kill you!
I can kill you with my own hands!
But I still love you.
You..
What is this game that you
are playing with me, Holofira?
You still think it is a game.
You never believed my love.
You never loved me.
Damn the day I met you.
You are telling the truth. It's not a game, huh?
A game? If my cousin Constantine...
...finds out about us, he
will kill us. But I don't care.
Constantine..
So Constantine is your cousin.
Take me away from here.
Let's not worry about the future.
you still want me..
...make your decision now, Orhan.
No one in this world can
love you more than I do...
...and me more than you, Lord's daughter.
Then... -Then we'll leave.
We'll leave right away, now.
Constantine is a devil.
He's the one who arrested
my father and took him to death.
I don't want to stay here anymore.
We'll go, my Holofira. We'll go.
But... but how will we go?
I will set out to go to the monastery!
I will change my route there and join you.
You thought well... We
will pass by the Tribe Kesis.
I will wait for you there, Lord's daughter.
But I have to go now.
Your and the Kayis' end is very close, Orhan.
I will make you pay for the pain you caused me.
GERMIYANOGLU BORDER - FRONTIER MARKET
Praise be to you, Yakup Bey. May
your happiness be everlasting.
You seem like you defeated your biggest enemy.
If Allah permits, that day will come.
We will pierce through the
chests of the infidels in this world.
There is no need to go that far.
What did our Rasulullah (PBUH) Efendi say?
Your biggest enemy...
...is your nafs between your eyebrows.
Sure... sure.
We are all struggling with our nafs.
It's such an enemy that...
...it demands taxes from those
who he calls his "religious brothers".
It sets his eyes on what's his.
There are such people. You know that. -I do.
I do.
And I know people who
hold a grudge against their...
...family just because they
are worried about rumours.
I know people who disown their children.
After a daughter disobeys her own father...
When words come out from
the nafs and not from the heart...
..it also burns its owner.
I can see it. It does not seem alright.
Let alone fighting with your nafs...
...even being unaware of its enmity...
...destroys a person. It leaves him alone.
He cannot even see the difference...
...between honor and disgrace, Haqq and falsehood.
As you talk to me...
...I see those who took what was
mine and those who disobeyed me.
Yet your words are precious to me.
And the cure of my heart.
Don't deprive me from this.
The one who wants the truth doesn't need words.
An ant's footsteps would be enough.
But for the one who wants power for his ambitions,
...even the town cries screaming
about truths with drums...
...would have no impacts.
Both my heart and my mind..
...are in the same line, thanks to Allah.
I'm looking forward to
hearing the ant's footsteps.
-Stay safe.
-Father! Father!
-Is he alright? My Bey!
Kanyumaz!
-Father! Father!
-Get him up.
-Come on.
-My Bey.
Father.
They have nothing to do with the market.
They watch the corners.
There must be something up.
They also have weapons. Who are they?
Dogs disguised as people.
People go home and these come out.
They'll attack and put the blame on market people.
You did a good job, Holofira.
I always take what I want, Constantin.
I made Orhan tell me about their return route.
After leaving Bursa, they'll go to Monk Plains.
Then they'll reach the tribe. This is their route.
I'm grateful to you.
But..
I have no intention to kill them on the way back.
I just wanted to be sure about your honesty.
If you are sure, then that
means I can go to Monastir.
Of course. But wait a for a while.
Because things will get crazy in Bursa.
I'll kill them before they leave the city.
If anyone survives,
...I will slaughter them in the Monk Valley.
They're taking Osman Bey's horses.
We'll leave..
...neither Osman Bey nor
our horses to these dastards.
Alright, Solgur Agha. Come on.
Come on.
You turned out to be right, my Bey.
They'll attack us on the way back.
-You think they took the bait?
-They did, my Bey.
They heard everything Holofira and I talked about.
They think we'll go back through Monk Valley.
Good. When they attack, we'll avenge Gunduz Bey.
Alright, my Bey.
My Bey...
What about Holofira? Will
we leave her to that dog?
What if he attempts to kill her?
Holofira must have won Constantin's favor.
Don't be worrying. Her
life will be safer than ours.
The Righteous!
Fatma Hatun! Tall Shahzade
and Gonca Hatun are coming.
You go to the training zone. I'll come after you.
-Come, my dear.
-In the name of Allah.
Did Yakup Bey forgive you, Gonca Hatun?
My sister...
Don't be upset. We'll always be with you.
I know, Fatma. I know.
Don't be sad, Gonca Hatun.
It doesn't matter even if
Mehmed Bey doesn't forgive.
I will be my nephew's uncle!
Thank you, his uncle Ghazi.
I'll go check the rug house.
Praise be to my boy.
Ghazi, you are a big man.
I know. I know, my Shahzade.
Don't mind my height.
I have even more under the surface.
Good boy.
-Son!
-Mother.
Good news?
Yakup Bey's heart isn't warming up, mother.
I know... His ice will never melt.
Yakup Bey isn't harming his
pride but he's hurting his daughter.
She doesn't want me to see..
...but this bothers Gonca too much, mother.
I don't know what to do.
I know, son. You need to be with her.
We'll always be with her.
Yes, we will.
Let's go.
The growing horses of
Turks are the blood of Turks!
Hands trying to touch them shall be broken!
Eyes set on them shall be scratched out!
Ya Allah!
You heathens! Solgur Agha!
They'll notice their absence shortly.
Let's take the horses out of the city quickly.
Let's go.
There is something up here.
This must be Constantin's doing.
They are not ordinary people, my Bey.
They intend to attack us, my Bey.
We know what they'll do.
But what will we do?
We don't want infidel Turks in our city!
We do not!
They're not ordinary people but armed
assassins, my Bey. They'll attack us.
It seems they laid the trap
outside, not inside the palace.
-Where are the horses?
-They're safe. We don't want!
-Don't be exposed. -Barbarian Turk!
-Brothers, you see for yourselves.
-Alps.
Retreat while they draw their swords.
-Brothers!
Brothers, every step those
betrayers take in our lands...
...is making Jesus turn in his grave!
Destroy those things! Block the ways!
Then we will destroy all of you!
Now we are going back! We will come back stronger.
Come on, brother!
You are still crying for your father
but there is no reason, Gonca.
What is going to change if they forgive you now?
Your family is treacherous.
This enmity will not end.
Control your tongue, Elcim.
-Am I lying?
You're being upset for nothing. Tell me.
Why are you not organizing your wedding?
It's been a long time since you got married.
You kept postponing it.
Bey, right? -Elcim!
No... You deserve it.
You want to kiss your father's
hand and organize your wedding.
But that's just a dream. Your father...
...is the enemy of Kayis.
Yakup Bey will not make peace with Kayis but...
...he might forgive you.
You are trying to say something else! I know that!
You want your husband and
your father to make peace, but...
But what, Elcim?
Why does it bother you that a daughter wants to...
...make peace with her father, my daughter?
Control yourself.
-I can control myself.
My father died for Osman Bey.
What did they do?
They've been making plans
behind your back since day one.
So there is no way out, huh?
We’ve arrived, my Bey!
Here.
Have you missed fighting side by side with me?
I have, but I wish this was not the first time!
Block all the streets, hold
the entrances and exits!
Find them!
There was no way that they could escape.
Apparently Osman took his
precaution before he came here.
But he won't be able to run away from me.
They are coming from this side, my Bey!
We are trapped here!
Then we will fight. Or...
...my Allah will show us a way out.
Osman Bey!
This way.
-Catch them!
-Let us find them!
-Bala Hatun.
-My girl.
Come on, sit.
Look at me.
What are you carrying in your
heart that spills out of your mouth?
I know you.
You are not a Hatun that
normally says these things.
I have no one left, Bala Hatun.
My family, my father. They all died.
I have no one to talk.
Look what you are saying.
We are here, my daughter.
Orhan, Fatma, Gonca is here.
I am here.
Does Orhan not act like your husband?
He does. Of course he does.
He is good, merciful.
What can a Hatun want more?
However, I don't know.
When looking at Gonca and Alaeddin Bey..
Look, my daughter.
"Everyone is different"
Say our ancestors.
Just as how people are different,
they also face different challenges.
You are not alone, my girl.
You are only pushing yourself to loneliness.
If you get out of this tent and called for help..
..everyone would come to you.
We are a family.
Also..
..those who do not talk about
their problems can't find a solution.
Look here.
You ruined your craft too.
You are not scared of having no children, right?
My girl, don't you ever.
You are just married. Don't lose hope.
You will pray, right?
What is this? Come on.
Get out of the way! Alaeddin!
Alaeddin
What is this.
What is Mehmet doing here?
-Brother!
Move! Move! -Father!
Father! What happened?
What happened to my father?
I don't know!
Yakup Bey is there!
What is happening? -Move!
-What happened?
-Alaeddin help! -Wait, Hatun.
Help, Alaeddin. -Gonca, stop.
Yakup Bey!
Yakup Bey, do you hear me? Yakup Bey!
Alaeddin, help!
Yakup Bey! Yakup Bey! -Father!
Father... what happened to him?
Father!
-Let's take him to the healing tent! Hurry!
Come on! Hurry!
Gonca! Gonca! My daughter!
-Hurry!
Hurry!
Come on!
-Mehmet! Tell me! What happened?
I don't know Alaeddin. He fell
to the ground all of a sudden.
Come on, father! Hang on!
-Hang on Yakup Bey!
They disappeared. We could not
find them, Commander Constantine.
Let them think they ran away.
I know the path they will take.
I will kill Osman with my
own hands in tribe Kesis.
Bring the horses!
#unrecognized text#
Clear the way for Trader Christo! Move, soldiers!
I have to take my goods to my ship!
My Bey, who is Christo? -Christo was a master.
I was his undermaster. Then we became companions.
We'll start after the people
calm down. Be careful.
Tugay. Husrev.
You'll stay a bit longer.
You'll wait for Osman Bey's orders.
Be careful, do not let them notice you.
-Don't worry, Cerkutay Bey.
For sure we'll take care of it.
Come on Alps... We will go
and get rid of these clothes.
Come on... -Come on.
In the name of Allah, the merciful,
the compassionate.
Come on, Yakup Bey.. Come on.
Father... Father...
Father... let us help you.
Father please wake up! Father...
Father...
Father. Father... Father...
Father... Father... Father..
Father... Father!
Father... Father...
Father..
Father, please, wake up!
Father! Father! Please, wake up!
Please, wake up! Please!
Take Gonca outside.
-My rose... Come on my rose...
Come on my Gonca.
-Come on Gonca.
Come on, Yakup Bey. Hang on.
Hang on, Yakup Bey.
Gonca..
Don't cry, Gonca.
My father is strong.
He will get over this.
He is Germiyanoglu Yakup Bey.
How did this happen? Huh? Was my father sick?
Since we went to Kutahya, he wouldn't...
...eat, he wouldn't sleep.
He was in sorrow inside,
but he didn't make it apparent.
It is all because of me.
-It is all because of me.
-No, my daughter.
Gonca, don't put this on your heart too.
Allah gives and takes everything.
With Allah's permission, he
will heal with Alaeddin's help.
I hope so.
Mehmed
Well done by bringing him here.
May Allah cures him.
Drink something, come on.
#unrecognized text#
Thank you, Elcim Hatun.
My Allah, help me.
My Allah, please help me.
My Allah.
#unrecognized text#
So, Nikola you said, Osman Bey.
You tricked me good.
They were saying cunning and honest about you.
-So it was true.
-May you prosper.
May you prosper, you
risked your life for us as well.
I didn't put it in danger just for you.
I put it in danger for Bursa as well.
I know your intentions, Osman Bey.
There is no justice left in Bursa.
I've heard about the justice you
provide in the lands you conquered.
This is not easy to say, however..
..people of Bursa are
waiting for you to save them..
..where there is injustice happening.
-I am one of them.
-Alright.
You saved my life also.
Looters couldn't get to my shop
again. Now I saved your life in return.
I don't like being in debt,
Osman Bey. Now we are even.
I know. Don't worry.
However, you should go back.
They shouldn't see you with us.
I will need you. Travel safe.
Everything is set, my Bey.
We are waiting for your orders.
Thank you, Solgur Agha. Let Konstantin come.
The route we will take will be his end.
If Allah permits, my Bey.
They are many, however, we will deal with them.
They are many, but we are Turks. Come on.
Alaeddin.
-Alaeddin, my father.
-His heart got under pressure.
His breath was weak when I came too.
Will my father be alright?
You cured my father before.
He became weak, Mehmed.
I will prepare him a medicine, he
will be back on his feet, if Allah permits.
-If Allah permits.
He will be alright, right Alaeddin?
You are lying to not make me upset.
-Alaeddin will he be alright?
-My Gonca.
We are doing the best we can.
We will pray and he will be alright.
-He will.
Tell me what you need, Alaeddin.
Just cure my father.
The only thing we need is time,
Mehmed. I can handle the rest.
I've brought my father here, as
there were no other healers, know that.
If he is lying in there now,
you are the reason, Alaeddin.
-Don't start, Mehmed.
-You shouldn't have taken my sister..
..if you didn't make her an enemy of my
father, none of this would've happened.
All this happened because
of you. You will cure my father.
-Or..
-Enough, brother.
-Enough!
-Not enough!
Both of you caused my father ill.
-You are crossing the line, Mehmed.
-What if I do?
-My Gonca! -Alaeddin!
-Are you alright, Gonca?
-Alaeddin, to the tent!
-Sister!
-To the tent!
Come on, Gonca.
Gonca, are you alright?
You will be alright.
Everything is ready, Commander Konstantin.
This is the route Holofira mentioned.
Osman will not leave here alive.
This road will be his end.
We'll use the route that
Holofira told Constantin about.
Why go into the trap knowingly, my Bey?
Aren't we famous for walking
into the traps, Solgur Agha?
We aren't only famous for walking
into traps but also for ruining the traps.
Exactly.
Constantin's father and
Holofira's father are brothers.
Constantin will show no mercy to Holofira.
For this reason, if we don't go
through the route Holofira mentioned,
...that won't be good for Holofira.
Today, our first move will
be getting out of Bursa alive!
In this way, we will protect Holofira's life.
What are you planning, my Bey?
Commander Constantin. Osman is coming alone.
Be ready!
I will take his life.
I will make those who did
this to you pay for this, father.
They took first my sister
and then the market from us.
Both Osman and Alaaddin will pay for this.
-Kanyumaz!
-My Shahzade.
Stay with my father.
-I will go check Gonca.
-As you order, my Shahzade.
Elcim Hatun.
You seem to regret what you said to Gonca Hatun.
You're angry with me too, Ulgen?
No way. You are a Kayi bride.
-Who am I to be angry with me?
-Estaghfirullah.
We are one. We share bread.
Tell me. Did I go too far?
You did.
But you aren't angry with Gonca.
You are upset because Orhan Bey has gone to Bursa.
Yes, I got jealous.
-Because Holofira is in Bursa.
-Elcim Hatun.
I don't have a position to give you advice.
But Holofira is risking her life for Osman Bey.
She's a spy in Bursa.
And Orhan Bey does...
...whatever you want.
Don't be upset in vain.
Holofira is a spy, huh?
Osman... Now I got you.
Welcome, Osman Bey.
What? Are you surprised?
Weren't you expecting to see me?
You escaped from Bursa.
But you can't escape from me now, Osman.
You laid a vile ambush for me, huh?
And now you're even showing
your teeth behind your soldiers!
Soldiers, tell me! Is this the
command who everybody praises?
Is your manhood only this much?
Here I am, Osman!
One on one!
Do you have courage to fight me?
Well... This is the field of reality!
We'll see who will survive and who will die!
I will cut off your head...
...and hang it on the city walls of Bursa, Osman!
Come to me. Come.
-Yes!
-Come on!
Oh Allah!
Visit turkision.com for more!